<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devsecops on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/devsecops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devsecops on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/devsecops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repositories with BFG Repo-Cleaner</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about secrets management? I&#39;ve committed a secret - now what? o.O Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repos (or any other Git repo) with BFG Repo-Cleaner  Step-by-step walkthrough Final note on permissions in Azure DevOps repos   Additional resources   Why should you care about secrets management?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to perform static code analysis of .NET Code with Security Code Scan</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</guid>
      
        <description>What is static code analysis and why do I need it? How to install and use Security Code Scan tool?  Installation in CI/CD pipeline Local installation How to view and read result report?   Additional resources   What is static code analysis and why do I need it?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security scanning of third-party dependencies with OWASP Dependency Check</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/owasp_depcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/owasp_depcheck/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about security of third-party dependencies What is OWASP Dependency Check (ODC) Adding OWASP Dependency Check to build pipeline How to analyze and fix build errors triggered by OWASP Dependency Check   Why should you care about security of third-party dependencies No matter how small the application you&#39;re developing is, at some point you&#39;ll end up using code that has been developed by someone else, i.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>