<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kris&#39;s Quick Cup of (A)K8S #2</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_2/</guid>
      
        <description>#1 - Run CronJob instantly #2 - Configure Rolling Update for Deployment #3 - Check what add-ons are available in AKS with Azure CLI   It&#39;s time for a new edition of Kris&#39;s Quick cup of Kubernetes where I&#39;m utilizing Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) for demo purposes!😺 In second edition of this tech tip series I would like to share a few tips related to CronJobs, Rolling Updates and AKS add-ons that can make your life easier when working with Kubernetes and specifically Azure Kubernetes Service.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery to AKS with Azure DevOps Environments - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ado_envs-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ado_envs-1/</guid>
      
        <description>What is an Azure DevOps Environment?  Introduction Benefits of using ADO Environments (IMHO)   Resource Grouping Tips  One Environment representing all development/staging/production clusters One Environment representing one development/staging/production cluster One Environment representing one application deployed in development/staging/production cluster   Next Steps   In the first part of this blog series I would like to talk about Azure DevOps Environments, benefits of using it for deployment of applications to AKS or any other Kubernetes distribution (or even a VM), and provide a few tips and tricks for how ADO environments and resources can be created.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris&#39;s Quick Cup of K8s #1</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_1/</guid>
      
        <description>#1 - Live streaming of Pod logs #2 - Get non-existent Namespace without erros #3 - Get all resources in a Namespace #4 - Retrieve and clean up Evicted Pods   Starting a totally new Tech Tips subsection feels great - especially when it&#39;s going to be purely dedicated to Kubernetes utilizing Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) for demo purposes!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repositories with BFG Repo-Cleaner</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about secrets management? I&#39;ve committed a secret - now what? o.O Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repos (or any other Git repo) with BFG Repo-Cleaner  Step-by-step walkthrough Final note on permissions in Azure DevOps repos   Additional resources   Why should you care about secrets management?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of --query in Azure CLI</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/azure_query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/azure_query/</guid>
      
        <description>Have you ever heard of or used query parameter when running Azure CLI commands? If not, I do recommend you checking it out because this is a pretty powerful parameter that can help you with much faster and efficient data retrieval and filtering! Let&#39;s use DNS records retrieval as an example: I need to update DNS records pointing to a specific IP, f.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>