<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devops on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devops on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating reusable build tasks in Azure DevOps pipelines with templates</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/ado_pipeline_template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/ado_pipeline_template/</guid>
      
        <description>Use case for pipeline templates Example 1: re-use template in multiple build pipelines Example 2: re-use parameterized template in multiple build stages   Use case for pipeline templates In the world of complex enterprise applications and distributed systems you may have a need to perform many more actions and validations as part of a build pipeline than before:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling failed Helm upgrade due to another operation in progress</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/helm_rollback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/helm_rollback/</guid>
      
        <description>Sometimes things may go wrong, also during ugprade of the application that is deployed to a Kubernetes cluster with Helm. When something goes wrong, you fix it and re-try a deployment with the new fix included. But then deployment operation fails with following error message:
Error: UPGRADE FAILED: another operation (install/upgrade/rollback) is in progress</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Pull Request flow with PR templates and PR Completion Stats in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/pr_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/pr_templates/</guid>
      
        <description>PR templates PR Completion Stats extension   Code reviews and pull requests are a totally normal practice these days if you&#39;re working together with other developers. Even if you&#39;re working solo you probably don&#39;t want to commit to main branch directly if you have CI/CD in place. That&#39;s when adding changes through pull requests and code reviews come into picture.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>