<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repositories with BFG Repo-Cleaner</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about secrets management? I&#39;ve committed a secret - now what? o.O Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repos (or any other Git repo) with BFG Repo-Cleaner  Step-by-step walkthrough Final note on permissions in Azure DevOps repos   Additional resources   Why should you care about secrets management?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to upgrade NGINX Ingress Controller with zero downtime in production</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ic_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ic_upgrade/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction to the needs for upgrading Ingress Controller Walkthrough of the process for upgrading NGINX Ingress Controller with zero downtime  Preparations Create temporary Ingress Controller Re-route traffic to temporary Ingress Controller Upgrade original Ingress Controller and re-route traffic from temporary IC Final test and cleanup   Additional resources   Introduction to the needs for upgrading Ingress Controller In some scenarios you may need to perform maintenance work on the Ingress Controller which can potentially result in downtime - in my case the time has come to move away from NGINX Ingress Controller for Kubernetes Helm chart located in stable repo and fully embrace the new Helm chart located in ingress-nginx repository.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to include new Kubernetes resource into existing Helm release</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_object_helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_object_helm/</guid>
      
        <description>What is Helm? How to let existing Helm release &amp;ldquo;adopt&amp;rdquo; a new Kubernetes resource and why it&#39;s important? Additional resources   Helm is extremely useful and efficient when it comes to distributing, installing and upgrading applications hosted in Kubernetes. But sometimes you may have a need to patch an existing release and there is a quick way to do that which I would like to share with you today.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Kubernetes Service for proxying to external services</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_proxy_svc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_proxy_svc/</guid>
      
        <description>Why would proxying to external services from Kubernetes cluster be relevant? What is Kubernetes Service and what kinds of Kubernetes Service can be created? Implementation description and preparation Proxy to external services with Service without Selectors Proxy to external services with ExternalName Service Additional resources   So, recently I&#39;ve faced a scenario where I got a chance to dig more into different Kubernetes Service types and experiment with those.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to perform static code analysis of .NET Code with Security Code Scan</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</guid>
      
        <description>What is static code analysis and why do I need it? How to install and use Security Code Scan tool?  Installation in CI/CD pipeline Local installation How to view and read result report?   Additional resources   What is static code analysis and why do I need it?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not load file or assembly...Oh my! How I went through five stages of grief and mastered assembly version conflict debugging with .NET CLI, ILSpy and Fusion Log</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</guid>
      
        <description>Why is dll hell created in the first place? Tools that helped me survive The Hell of DLL  Fusion Log ILSpy dotnet list package &amp;ndash;include-transitive   How to resolve assembly version conflicts To sign or not to sign - the future of strong-named assemblies   If you&#39;re a .</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to distribute console applications easily with .NET tools</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</guid>
      
        <description>What is a .NET Tool and how do I create one? How to install, use and uninstall a .NET Tool? Additional resources   There are probably no developers out there (or at least very few) who have never created a console application - use cases where such apps are a first choice are hundreds, if not thousands.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security scanning of third-party dependencies with OWASP Dependency Check</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/owasp_depcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/owasp_depcheck/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about security of third-party dependencies What is OWASP Dependency Check (ODC) Adding OWASP Dependency Check to build pipeline How to analyze and fix build errors triggered by OWASP Dependency Check   Why should you care about security of third-party dependencies No matter how small the application you&#39;re developing is, at some point you&#39;ll end up using code that has been developed by someone else, i.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create new microservices easily with dotnet custom templates</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</guid>
      
        <description>What is a dotnet template though? How to create a custom dotnet template? How do I transform a microservice template to a dotnet template? How do I test the dotnet template and verify that it performs as expected?  Testing single template Testing template collection   How do I pack and make template collection NuGet package available for others?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My journey through Journey</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/gaming_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/gaming_journey/</guid>
      
        <description>I haven&#39;t been much of a gamer actually but there have been some games that managed to keep my interest and attention for quite some time. The highlight of my gaming activity was in the beginning of 2000s - when I used to come home from school and complete all of my homework - as a reward I would be allowed to spend some hours playing games on the good old Windows XP.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>