<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dotnet on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/dotnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dotnet on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/dotnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Could not load file or assembly...Oh my! How I went through five stages of grief and mastered assembly version conflict debugging with .NET CLI, ILSpy and Fusion Log</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</guid>
      <description>Why is dll hell created in the first place? Tools that helped me survive The Hell of DLL  Fusion Log ILSpy dotnet list package &amp;ndash;include-transitive   How to resolve assembly version conflicts To sign or not to sign - the future of strong-named assemblies   If you&#39;re a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to distribute console applications easily with .NET tools</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</guid>
      <description>What is a .NET Tool and how do I create one? How to install, use and uninstall a .NET Tool? Additional resources   There are probably no developers out there (or at least very few) who have never created a console application - use cases where such apps are a first choice are hundreds, if not thousands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create new microservices easily with dotnet custom templates</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</guid>
      <description>What is a dotnet template though? How to create a custom dotnet template? How do I transform a microservice template to a dotnet template? How do I test the dotnet template and verify that it performs as expected?  Testing single template Testing template collection   How do I pack and make template collection NuGet package available for others?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
