<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dotnet on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/dotnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dotnet on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/tags/dotnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate .NET target framework update with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/update_dotnet_fw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/update_dotnet_fw/</guid>
      
        <description>With all the active development in the .NET world many of us have faced a situation where we need to update .NET target framework more frequently in order to be able to keep up, but at the same time to be able to utilize all the goodies .NET has to offer.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving .NET code quality with NDepend in Visual Studio and Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/ndepend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/ndepend/</guid>
      
        <description>What is NDepend? Improving and enforcing source code quality with NDepend Azure DevOps extension  Adding NDepend Build Task NDepend build output and Azure DevOps Dashboard Adding code coverage to NDepend analysis Adding code coverage from external location to NDepend analysis Trends section in NDepend Dashboard in Azure DevOps Enabling NDepend quality gate checks in build pipeline   Quality gate and rule management with NDepend VS Extension  Running initial NDepend analysis in Visual Studio Modifying default quality gate Deactivate, Suppress and Resolve quality gate issues Adding custom rule and connecting it to existing quality gate   Additional resources    What is NDepend?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to perform static code analysis of .NET Code with Security Code Scan</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</guid>
      
        <description>What is static code analysis and why do I need it? How to install and use Security Code Scan tool?  Installation in CI/CD pipeline Local installation How to view and read result report?   Additional resources    What is static code analysis and why do I need it?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not load file or assembly...Oh my! How I went through five stages of grief and mastered assembly version conflict debugging with .NET CLI, ILSpy and Fusion Log</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</guid>
      
        <description>Why is dll hell created in the first place? Tools that helped me survive The Hell of DLL  Fusion Log ILSpy dotnet list package &amp;ndash;include-transitive   How to resolve assembly version conflicts To sign or not to sign - the future of strong-named assemblies    If you&#39;re a .</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to distribute console applications easily with .NET tools</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</guid>
      
        <description>What is a .NET Tool and how do I create one? How to install, use and uninstall a .NET Tool? Additional resources    There are probably no developers out there (or at least very few) who have never created a console application - use cases where such apps are a first choice are hundreds, if not thousands.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create new microservices easily with dotnet custom templates</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</guid>
      
        <description>What is a dotnet template though? How to create a custom dotnet template? How do I transform a microservice template to a dotnet template? How do I test the dotnet template and verify that it performs as expected?  Testing single template Testing template collection   How do I pack and make template collection NuGet package available for others?</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>