<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kris - The Coding Unicorn</title>
    <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kris - The Coding Unicorn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kris&#39;s Quick Cup of (A)K8S #2</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_2/</guid>
      
        <description>#1 - Run CronJob instantly #2 - Configure Rolling Update for Deployment #3 - Check what add-ons are available in AKS with Azure CLI   It&#39;s time for a new edition of Kris&#39;s Quick cup of Kubernetes where I&#39;m utilizing Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) for demo purposes!😺 In second edition of this tech tip series I would like to share a few tips related to CronJobs, Rolling Updates and AKS add-ons that can make your life easier when working with Kubernetes and specifically Azure Kubernetes Service.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Pull Request flow with PR templates and PR Completion Stats in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/pr_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/pr_templates/</guid>
      
        <description>PR templates PR Completion Stats extension   Code reviews and pull requests are a totally normal practice these days if you&#39;re working together with other developers. Even if you&#39;re working solo you probably don&#39;t want to commit to main branch directly if you have CI/CD in place. That&#39;s when adding changes through pull requests and code reviews come into picture.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Delivery to AKS with Azure DevOps Environments - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ado_envs-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ado_envs-1/</guid>
      
        <description>What is an Azure DevOps Environment?  Introduction Benefits of using ADO Environments (IMHO)   Resource Grouping Tips  One Environment representing all development/staging/production clusters One Environment representing one development/staging/production cluster One Environment representing one application deployed in development/staging/production cluster   Next Steps   In the first part of this blog series I would like to talk about Azure DevOps Environments, benefits of using it for deployment of applications to AKS or any other Kubernetes distribution (or even a VM), and provide a few tips and tricks for how ADO environments and resources can be created.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate .NET target framework update with PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/update_dotnet_fw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/update_dotnet_fw/</guid>
      
        <description>With all the active development in the .NET world many of us have faced a situation where we need to update .NET target framework more frequently in order to be able to keep up, but at the same time to be able to utilize all the goodies .NET has to offer.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving .NET code quality with NDepend in Visual Studio and Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/ndepend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/ndepend/</guid>
      
        <description>What is NDepend? Improving and enforcing source code quality with NDepend Azure DevOps extension  Adding NDepend Build Task NDepend build output and Azure DevOps Dashboard Adding code coverage to NDepend analysis Adding code coverage from external location to NDepend analysis Trends section in NDepend Dashboard in Azure DevOps Enabling NDepend quality gate checks in build pipeline   Quality gate and rule management with NDepend VS Extension  Running initial NDepend analysis in Visual Studio Modifying default quality gate Deactivate, Suppress and Resolve quality gate issues Adding custom rule and connecting it to existing quality gate   Additional resources   What is NDepend?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris&#39;s Quick Cup of K8s #1</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/kris_daily_k8s_1/</guid>
      
        <description>#1 - Live streaming of Pod logs #2 - Get non-existent Namespace without erros #3 - Get all resources in a Namespace #4 - Retrieve and clean up Evicted Pods   Starting a totally new Tech Tips subsection feels great - especially when it&#39;s going to be purely dedicated to Kubernetes utilizing Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) for demo purposes!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repositories with BFG Repo-Cleaner</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/secrets_cleanup/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about secrets management? I&#39;ve committed a secret - now what? o.O Cleaning up secrets in Azure DevOps and GitHub repos (or any other Git repo) with BFG Repo-Cleaner  Step-by-step walkthrough Final note on permissions in Azure DevOps repos   Additional resources   Why should you care about secrets management?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of --query in Azure CLI</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/azure_query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/techtips/azure_query/</guid>
      
        <description>Have you ever heard of or used query parameter when running Azure CLI commands? If not, I do recommend you checking it out because this is a pretty powerful parameter that can help you with much faster and efficient data retrieval and filtering! Let&#39;s use DNS records retrieval as an example: I need to update DNS records pointing to a specific IP, f.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to upgrade NGINX Ingress Controller with zero downtime in production</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ic_upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_ic_upgrade/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction to the needs for upgrading Ingress Controller Walkthrough of the process for upgrading NGINX Ingress Controller with zero downtime  Preparations Create temporary Ingress Controller Re-route traffic to temporary Ingress Controller Upgrade original Ingress Controller and re-route traffic from temporary IC Final test and cleanup   Additional resources   Introduction to the needs for upgrading Ingress Controller In some scenarios you may need to perform maintenance work on the Ingress Controller which can potentially result in downtime - in my case the time has come to move away from NGINX Ingress Controller for Kubernetes Helm chart located in stable repo and fully embrace the new Helm chart located in ingress-nginx repository.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public talks and Publications</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/public/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/public/</guid>
      
        <description>30.September 2021 - Semi-live video session - &amp;ldquo;Cloud Stories from Norway, Episode 9: Frequent releases with Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)&amp;rdquo; “Cloud stories from Norway” is a 40-minutes long videoshow where Microsoft Norway together with invited guests features Azure cloud best practices, patterns, tips &amp;amp; tricks used in production in the products and services of well-known Norwegian companies.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to include new Kubernetes resource into existing Helm release</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_object_helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_object_helm/</guid>
      
        <description>What is Helm? How to let existing Helm release &amp;ldquo;adopt&amp;rdquo; a new Kubernetes resource and why it&#39;s important? Additional resources   Helm is extremely useful and efficient when it comes to distributing, installing and upgrading applications hosted in Kubernetes. But sometimes you may have a need to patch an existing release and there is a quick way to do that which I would like to share with you today.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Kubernetes Service for proxying to external services</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_proxy_svc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/k8s_proxy_svc/</guid>
      
        <description>Why would proxying to external services from Kubernetes cluster be relevant? What is Kubernetes Service and what kinds of Kubernetes Service can be created? Implementation description and preparation Proxy to external services with Service without Selectors Proxy to external services with ExternalName Service Additional resources   So, recently I&#39;ve faced a scenario where I got a chance to dig more into different Kubernetes Service types and experiment with those.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to perform static code analysis of .NET Code with Security Code Scan</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_sast_scs/</guid>
      
        <description>What is static code analysis and why do I need it? How to install and use Security Code Scan tool?  Installation in CI/CD pipeline Local installation How to view and read result report?   Additional resources   What is static code analysis and why do I need it?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Could not load file or assembly...Oh my! How I went through five stages of grief and mastered assembly version conflict debugging with .NET CLI, ILSpy and Fusion Log</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/assembly_version_conflicts/</guid>
      
        <description>Why is dll hell created in the first place? Tools that helped me survive The Hell of DLL  Fusion Log ILSpy dotnet list package &amp;ndash;include-transitive   How to resolve assembly version conflicts To sign or not to sign - the future of strong-named assemblies   If you&#39;re a .</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to distribute console applications easily with .NET tools</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_tools/</guid>
      
        <description>What is a .NET Tool and how do I create one? How to install, use and uninstall a .NET Tool? Additional resources   There are probably no developers out there (or at least very few) who have never created a console application - use cases where such apps are a first choice are hundreds, if not thousands.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security scanning of third-party dependencies with OWASP Dependency Check</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/owasp_depcheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/owasp_depcheck/</guid>
      
        <description>Why should you care about security of third-party dependencies What is OWASP Dependency Check (ODC) Adding OWASP Dependency Check to build pipeline How to analyze and fix build errors triggered by OWASP Dependency Check   Why should you care about security of third-party dependencies No matter how small the application you&#39;re developing is, at some point you&#39;ll end up using code that has been developed by someone else, i.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create new microservices easily with dotnet custom templates</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/dotnet_custom_templates/</guid>
      
        <description>What is a dotnet template though? How to create a custom dotnet template? How do I transform a microservice template to a dotnet template? How do I test the dotnet template and verify that it performs as expected?  Testing single template Testing template collection   How do I pack and make template collection NuGet package available for others?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/archives/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/contact/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My journey through Journey</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/gaming_journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/post/gaming_journey/</guid>
      
        <description>I haven&#39;t been much of a gamer actually but there have been some games that managed to keep my interest and attention for quite some time. The highlight of my gaming activity was in the beginning of 2000s - when I used to come home from school and complete all of my homework - as a reward I would be allowed to spend some hours playing games on the good old Windows XP.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kristhecodingunicorn.com/about/</guid>
      
        <description>Hey and welcome to my Tech Corner!
My name is Kris (obvously) and I have created this blog to share tech and non-tech (sometimes) stuff with the rest of the world 😸
I live in Norway, love coding and putting cat pictures in presentations😼 Currently I am working as a Lead Software Architect and driving several exciting tech projects that support digitalization journey in public and private sector, minimizing bureaucracy and making citizens&#39; life easier.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>